amara.com 2019-05-08

# Privacy Notice

Amara Living Limited gathers and processes your personal data in accordance with this privacy notice and in compliance with the relevant data protection regulation and law. This notice provides you with the necessary information regarding your rights and obligations, and explains how, why and when we collect and process your personal data.

## Who we are

Amara Living Limited’s registered office is at **Amara Living Limited, Unit 4, Concord Farm, School Road, Rayne, Braintree, Essex, CM77 6SP, United Kingdom.** We are a company registered in England and Wales under company number **5348182**. We are registered on the Data Protection Commissioner's Register of Data Controllers under registration number **Z9385052** , and act as the data controller. Our designated Data Protection Officer is Ross Motley. Please refer to the section below for contact details.

## What information do we collect about you?

We process your personal data to meet our legal, statutory and contractual obligations and to provide you with our products and services.

The personal data we collect is as follows:

  * Your on-site browsing behavior, including the pages you have viewed, IP address and browser details etc.
  * Your name, email, telephone and preferences.
  * Your organisation details, if provided.
  * Your addresses, payment details and any other data you provide as required for processing your orders and returns.
  * Communication between us, including emails, online chat messages and telephone calls.
  * Gift card details.
  * Blog and LuxPad comments.
  * Other data entered into our site for specific purposes, for example the creation of wishlists.

Any other data collection is detailed at the point it is collected in a separate notice.

## How do we we collect information about you?

We collect data from you in the following ways:

  * The data you enter into online forms on our websites.
  * Your browsing behaviour on our websites.
  * When you contact us, for example over email, telephone or online chat.

## How will we use the information about you?

Our processing activities are:

  * Tracking and analysing your browsing behaviour on our website for our own performance purposes.
  * Sharing your onsite behaviour with third parties for marketing purposes.
  * Fulfilling your orders, including placing them, taking payment, dispatching them and dealing with any returns.
  * Responding to customer services requests via chat, email, telephone etc.
  * Analysis of data for reporting, forecasting and site performance.
  * Analysis of data for marketing purposes, including profiling. This may involve combining your data with that from third parties, such as Mosaic profiling data.

## Sharing and disclosing your personal data

We do not share or disclose any of your personal data to third parties without your consent, other than for the purposes specified in this notice or where there is a legal requirement.

### Onsite browsing and marketing controllers

As is normal for the ecommerce industry, we share your browsing data with some third party marketing organisations, primarily through Javascript tracking code. Those organisations become the controllers of that data, so if you opt-out of any further tracking on our site you would need to contact those organisations directly to exercise your other data rights. These data transfers are in Amara’s legitimate interest.

#### Affiliate Window

[Affiliate Window](https://www.awin.com/gb) power some of our referral programmes. You may be interested in their [Privacy Notice](https://www.awin.com/gb/legal/privacy-policy),

You can opt out of the tracking and data transfers on our browsing data preferences page.

#### BuyaPowa

Your order details will be shared with [BuyaPowa](https://www.buyapowa.com/) when you place an order on our site, which powers some of our referral programmes. If you subscribe to our referral programme, the data you provide will be sent to BuyaPowa who run the programme.

You can opt out of the data transfers on our browsing data preferences page.

#### Criteo

[Criteo](https://www.criteo.com/) power some of our display remarketing programmes. They track your browsing behaviour across multiple websites, and build a profile of your interests. This allows Amara to show you relevant adverts on other websites. You may be interested in their [Privacy Notice](https://www.criteo.com/privacy/).

You can opt out of the tracking and data transfers on our browsing data preferences page.

#### Conversant

[Conversant](https://www.conversantmedia.com/) power some of our display remarketing programmes. They track your browsing behaviour across multiple websites, and build a profile of your interests. This allows Amara to show you relevant adverts on other websites. You may be interested in their [Privacy Notice](https://www.conversantmedia.com/legal/privacy).

You can opt out of the tracking and data transfers on our browsing data preferences page.

#### Facebook

We use [Facebook](https://en-gb.facebook.com/business/products/ads) to advertise to you on their platform.

You can opt out of the tracking and data transfers on our browsing data preferences page.

#### Genie

[Genie](https://www.genieventures.co.uk/) are used as part of our advertising campaigns to monitor their performance.

You can opt out of the tracking and data transfers on our browsing data preferences page.

#### Google Adwords

We run advertising campaigns via the [Google](https://adwords.google.com/intl/en_uk/home/) platform.

You can opt out of the tracking and data transfers on our browsing data preferences page.

#### Rakuten

[Rakuten](https://rakutenmarketing.com/en-uk/) power many of our affiliate campaigns.

You can opt out of the tracking and data transfers on our browsing data preferences page.

#### Pinterest

We advertise on [Pinterest](https://ads.pinterest.com/).

You can opt out of the tracking and data transfers on our browsing data preferences page.

### Order fulfillment controllers

We share your personal data with some other organisations as part of the order fulfillment process. This data processing is part of your contract with us when you place an order.

These companies are joint controllers with Amara of your customer data, so you will need to contact them directly to exercise your data rights. Our order fulfillment partners are:

  * [Adyen](https://www.adyen.com/) provide us with payment processing and fraud analysis.
  * [Apple Pay](https://www.apple.com/uk/apple-pay/) provide us with payment processing and fraud analysis.
  * [Aramex](https://www.aramex.com/) provide us with courier services.
  * [Cardstream](https://www.cardstream.com/) provide us with payment processing and fraud analysis.
  * [DHL](https://www.logistics.dhl/gb-en/home.html) provide us with courier services.
  * [DPD](http://www.dpd.co.uk/) provide us with courier services.
  * [First Data](https://www.firstdata.com/en_gb/home.html) provide us with payment processing and fraud analysis.
  * [Klarna](https://www.klarna.com/uk/) provide us with payment processing and fraud analysis.
  * [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/uk/home) provide us with payment processing and fraud analysis.

### Other controllers

#### Feefo

[Feefo](https://www.feefo.com/business/gb_en) provide review and market research services. When placing an order, we may send your details to [Feefo](https://www.feefo.com/business/gb_en), who will then email you to request a review of our products. This transfer is done in Amara’s legitimate interest to perform market research about our products and services.

You can opt out in our data preferences page.

You will need to contact [Feefo](https://www.feefo.com/business/gb_en) directly to exercise your data rights, as they are acting as a data controller and we do not control how they process your data.

### Our data processors

We engage the following organisations which we use as processors of your data. All processors acting on our behalf only process your data in accordance with instructions from us and comply fully with this privacy notice, the data protection laws and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

## Marketing, promotions and offers

In most cases, we will only send you email marketing communications if you have opted in to receive them.

When you place an order with us, we may rely upon a soft opt-in approach to send you emails along with our legitimate interest to process your data. If we are using this approach, you will be offered an out-out when your data are collected.

In all cases you have the right to opt-out at any time, please see the footer of the emails for details.

You may opt out of other marketing communications via post, telephone or SMS, from the My Account area.

## How long will we keep your data for?

The data you can manage from your My Account area will be stored until you remove it, for example your wishlists and saved addresses.

Data about your orders and communications with us will be held indefinitely as we need a legal record of these.

Website behavioural data will be kept for up to 38 months, after which time we aim to store  only store aggregated, non-personal data.

You may also delete your account which removes most of the data we hold about you - see the “Right to erasure” section for more details.

## Securing your data

We takes your privacy and data security seriously and we take every reasonable measure and precaution to protect and secure your personal data. We work hard to protect your information from unauthorised access, alteration, disclosure or destruction and have several layers of security measures in place.

## Your rights

You have many rights around the use of your personal data. We are implementing them in the following ways:

### Right to be informed

Your right to be informed about how we use personal data is contained within this notice, including:

  * The purposes for which we process your data.
  * The categories of personal data we hold about you.
  * The recipients to whom your personal data has/will be disclosed.
  * How long we intend to store your personal data for.
  * If we did not collect the data directly from you, information about its source.

### Right of access

You have the right to request the personal data which we hold about you. We have implemented a process within the My Account area which allows you to request access.

If you have placed orders as a guest only, you must create an account for us to be able to verify your identity before we can process your request.

### Right to rectification

You are able to rectify most data from within your My Account area. If there is any other data which you want to be rectified, please contact customer services.

### Right to erasure

You have the right to request that we delete the personal data we hold about you. We have implemented a process within the My Account area which allows you to delete your account and most of the associated data.

There is some data which we do not delete:

  * Your name and email, which we use to store the deletion request.
  * Your order data, which we require for reporting and tax purposes. However, we will stop using your personal data for marketing profiling.
  * Your communications with us.

If you have placed orders as a guest only, you must create an account for us to be able to verify your identity before we can process your request.

### Right to restrict processing

You have the right to restrict our data processing, which you may do in two places:

  * My Account, if you have an account.
  * My browsing preferences, if you do not have an account.

If the processing is done by a different data controller, you will need to contact them directly.

### Right to data portability

You may download the data we hold about you in the My Account area. We have not implemented any specific data portability initiatives, as we do not believe there are any standard approaches in the ecommerce sector. We will implement more data portability initiatives if this changes in the future.

### Right to object

You have the right to object to our data processing, to do this, please contact customer services.

## Translated privacy notices

The non-English translations of this notice are for convenience only, in the event of conflict or ambiguity the English version is authoritative.

## Changes to our privacy notice

Any changes to this notice will be posted onto this page. If the changes are significant we may display a notice or seek your consent.

## How to contact us or lodge a complaint

You may contact customer services to lodge a complaint.
